# **AKHIL RAJ**

Frontend Developer

E: akhilrajktt@gmail.com

**P:** +91-9710635120

W: codebounce.vercel.app

L: @akhil-raj-2699371aa

A: H-207, S&P Living Space, Kamarajar Street, Ayanambakham, Chennai, 600095, India

**Nationality:** 

Indian

SKILLS	
Javascript	
HTML	
CSS	
SCSS	
Typescript	
React Js	
Redux	

## **LANGUAGES**

English

Next Js

Tailwind CSS

Malayalam

Telugu

Tamil

Hindi

## **PROFILE**

Meticulous frontend developer with 2 years experience and passion for developing responsive web apps and websites. To plan and design the structure and design of web pages. To develop website features that can enhance the user experience. To strategize design choices according to user experience. To implement design for mobile sites.

- Develop web apps using frameworks such as React Js and Next Js.
- Managing states using Redux.
- Creating responsive web apps using CSS, SCSS, Tailwind CSS, MUI.
- Develop backend API using Node Js and express Js.

## **EDUCATION**

MTech Integrated Software | Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore

Jul 2016 - May 2021

XII | Velammal Vidhyashram, Chennai

Jul 2014 - May 2016

X | St.John's Hr Sec School, Vijayawada

Jun 2004 - May 2014

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Full Stack Developer | Bluechip encore private limited, Banglore

Aug 2021 - Nov 2021

- Worked as a full stack developer to develop their website and dashboard using React Is, Node Js and mongo DB (MERN Stack).
- Managed, optimized, and updated Node Js , Mongo DB databases as necessary.
- Helped in building their sub brand websites with MERN Stack, helping market their sub brand products

## **INTERNAL WORK**

#### Freelance Web Developer (Vishnu cars)

Jan 2021 - Mar 2021

- Worked on designing and developing website to market their driving schools.
- Developed desktop application for the admin to check the booking that came through the website.
- Stack Used React Js, SCSS, Firebase, Electron Js

#### Freelance Web Developer (Sreedhar Memorial Hospital)

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

- Worked to design, build and ship website for a hospital to market their hospital.
- Stack used React Js, Firebase, CSS